# Maya Wright

UX/UI Designer & Front-End Website Developer

- · HTML · CSS · JavaScript · Bootstrap · Adobe XD · Figma · Blender · Sketchbook · · WordPress · Familiarity with Browser Compatibility ·
  - mayagwright20@hotmail.com
    wordpress.com/dontbugmie
    github.com/dontbugmie
    +447506111484

Self-taught UX/UI Designer and Front-End Website Developer with a strong focus on user engagement, developer experience and maintainability. Progress driven person, who loves contributing to open source projects.

## > Projects

#### minecraftforum.net 'design + wireframes

The Minecraft Forum is the #1 destination for Minecraft Players to enhance, explore and share their passion for Minecraft. Acquired by **Curse** which is now a part of **Twitch**. Millions of members, tens of millions of posts, billions of page views. My role in this project was to assist with designing and constructing wireframes that would enhance user interaction and experience.

#### blacklivesmatterstories · design + development

Developed a custom web platform HTML, CSS and Javascript. Blacklivesmatterstories is an ongoing personal project I have been working on where users can share their experiences, videos and images of the Black Lives Matter movement. An erasable hero canvas is used for enhanced user experience and engagement to reveal a video explaining the movement.

#### delivered.by · design + front-end development

Delivered.by is a database that helps users find products that can be delivered by a certain date. A strong focus on user experience was executed. Using a simple interface helps customers in a rush to buy something able to shop quicker.

Example: flowers.delivered.by/tomorrow

#### httpstatuses.com · design

HTTP Status Code reference site providing a better interface to RFC 2616. Used daily by thousands of developers and earned more than 500 stars on GitHub. A simple and clear layout helps users navigate.

#### husski · design + development

A custom designed platform where HUSSKI members can share videos, images and statuses. Implemented using WordPress, Husski is the first society website that members can find merchandise, music playlists, trip tickets, social events and more all in one place!

## > Employment & Experience

Code First Girls - Present

I currently teach front-end website development lessons for Code First Girls.

I have recently implemented changed to the teaching curriculum to enhance student engagement and techniques that are seen as better within the working environment. Student are taught from beginner level HTML right through to wireframe constructions and how to use frameworks and libraries, such as Bootstrap and React.js.

ThoughtWorks - February 2020 - March 2020

An 8 week course alongside Code First Girls learning front-end best practices.

During the course at ThoughtWorks I was able to develop new and existing skills to enrich my front-end development skills. Alongside this course I was able to learn about transferable practices such as KISS, OOP, TDD, SOLID and agile. I was also mentored through personal side projects that encompassed Three.js and Babylon.js.

HUSSKI - June 2018 - June 2019

Voted in by Husski society members, my role involved organizing, designing and creating all the promotion materials and literature for the club. This included designing a new logo, making a website, designing the merchandise, posters and gazebos used throughout the year.

Sony - April 2008 - September 2008

Working alongside Olympic athletes to blog street athletics competitions.

Interviewing youth participants, spectators and special guests including Linford Christies, Darren Campbell and Mark Lewis-Francis. Filming and editing for the Song Media crew YouTube channel.

## > Education

University of Reading - MSc Real Estate · Merit

University of Hull - BSc Psychology · 2:1

University of Arts London - Art & Design Foundation · Distinction

Harris Campbell - A-Levels · Math's - A · Psychology - A · Textiles - B